A Guide to the Helen Sue F. Carlton Collection, 1788-1967
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Helen Sue F. Carlton Collection, 1788-1967
Library of Virginia
35133
1.35 cu. ft. (in part, photocopies).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Helen F. Carlton, Richmond, Virginia, 5 April 1995.
Biographical/Historical Information
Resident of Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Includes business records, county and state government records, and personal papers. The business records contain mostly accounts and invoices from various Richmond, Virginia, businesses. The county and state government records include accounts, appointments, commissions, deeds, and letters from various Virginia counties and state agencies. The personal papers contain correspondence and accounts. There is also a medical register of Dr. Broadie S. Herndon of Fredericksburg, Virginia, dated 1861-1867, as well as a receipt book and tobacco production log from Manchester, Virginia, dated 1851-1866.
Contents List
- BUSINESS RECORDS
  - J.W. Bliley Co. - Account, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - C.F. Cross Shoe Co. - Letter, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - W.W. Foster - Account, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Garrett & Company - Letter, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gilman Bros. - Account, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - D.J. Gregory Vinegar Company - Letter, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Harwood Bros. & Co. - Letter, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - J.W. Hurley (Urbanna) - Records, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Miller & Rhoads - Account, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Polk Miller Drug Co. - Accounts, 1894-1898> (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Model Steam Laundry - Agreement, 1904> (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - T.F. Park & Co. - Account, 1895> (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - C.F. Sauer Company - Account, 1895> (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Smithdeal Business College - Admission Certificate, 1924> (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Thalhimer Brothers - Account, 1915> (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tiffany Studios (New York) - Letter, 1905> (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Virginia Historical Society - Letter re: Prince George Co. records, 1901> (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Weisiger Clothing Co. - Letter, 1890> (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Receipt Book and Tobacco Production Log, 1851-1866> (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Medical Register of Dr. Brodie S. Herndon, 1861-1867> (Box 1, Folder 20)
- COUNTY AND STATE RECORDS
  - Alleghany County - Justices of the Peace Records, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alleghany County - Sheriff's Appointment, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Amelia County - Guardian's Account, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Amelia County - Slave Bill of Sale, 1823 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Charlotte County - Justices of the Peace Appointment, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chesterfield County - Administrator's Account, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Chesterfield County - Deed, Eanes to Eanes, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chesterfield County - Militia Commission, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chesterfield County - Slave Bill of Sale, 1825 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Fluvanna County - Overseers of the Poor Letter, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Fluvanna County - Sheriff's Appointment, 1816 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fluvanna County - Tobacco Inspectors Appointments, 1792-1835 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Franklin County - Militia Commissions, 1803 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Henrico County - Sheriff's Execution, 1849 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Lunenburg County - Agreement, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mecklenburg County - Coroner's Appointment, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mecklenburg County - Justices of the Peace Appointment, 1845 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mecklenburg County - Sheriff's Appointments, 1815-1816, 1843 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mecklenburg County - Tobacco Inspector Appointments, 1835 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Mercer County - Tobacco Inspector Appointment, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Nansemond County - Deed, Griffin and Hoffman to Whitehead, 1850 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Northampton County - Notary Public Appointment, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Southampton County - Justice of the Peace Appointments, 1847, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Southampton County - Sheriff's Appointments, 1817-1847 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wythe County - Militia Commission, 1795 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Petersburg - Injuction Bond, 1821 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Richmond - Agreements, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Richmond - Certificate of Proficiency, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Richmond - Deed, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Richmond - Election Certificate, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Office of the Governor - Letter, Gov. Charles T. O'Ferral to William R. McKenney, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Militia Commission, 1804 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Penitentiary Punishment Report, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Virginia Treasury Department - Letter, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- PERSONAL PAPERS
  - Andrews, John G. - 1862-1887 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Batkins, Ernest A. - 1918-1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Brandt, Mrs. L.G. - 1909, 1925-1931 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Burgwin, Frances Eliza B. - 1823 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Crenshaw, Lewis - 1833 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Dietrich, John A. - 1920-1942 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Dorin, Frances B. - 1931-1932 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Guest, James - 1861 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Harris, Henry T. - 1892-1921 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Hurst, William - 1913-1922 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - LaFouche Family - 1919 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Merrill, George F. - 1867 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - "Perricks Meditation," ca. 1870-1880 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Moore, R.O. - 1906-1925 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Nichols, T.J. - 1932-1934 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Russell, Charles F. - 1882-1909 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Smith, James C. - 1900 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vaughan, C.C. - 1912-1927 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Walton Family - 1926-1943 (Box 3, Folder 4-7)
  - Waymac, R.A. - 1868 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - White Family - 1871-1921 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Williamson, J. Frank - 1923-1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Accounts and Receipts - 1815-1922 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence - 1818-1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)